# **Andrew Davidson**

7 GARDEN CLOSE BARNET HERTS EN5 3EW

Date of Birth: 10th January 1991 British GitHub: Nationality: adav

Mobile: 07743007489 Email: adav@me.com

I have attained BSc Computer Science (1st Class Honours) from the University of Birmingham, UK. Since 2013, I have worked for UBS Investment Bank as a Software Engineer, first in OTC Derivatives and currently in Research (Advisory). Outside of work I enjoy creating my own software projects, for fun, which also allows me to learn new Code Craftsmanship techniques, languages and technologies. I have a keen interest in Technology Startups, closely follow technology news and attend Silicon Roundabout meet-ups.

I have well-developed interpersonal skills and the ability to work both in a team and independently. I would conscientiously add value to any area of your organisation due to my enthusiastic work ethic, strong communication skills and the ability to function well under pressure.

## **Employment History**

September 2013 - Present

#### Position: Group Technology Analyst (Software Development) at UBS Investment Bank

- · First Rotation Designing and developing a suite of applications supporting UBS's OTC Derivatives business. Predominately coding Java.
- Current Rotation Designing and developing a RESTful Investment Banking Research API that interfaces department apps and data between Research Analysts and the rest of the bank. Coding Java. (The API is a component of award-winning UBS Neo)
- One of the lead organisers of the highlysuccessful first UBS Global Hackathon. My team's UK event won the overall competition and was granted internal seed funding.
- · On committee for UBS Public Speaking network.

- · Applying and practising Agile Development, Test-Driven Development behaviours and Pair Programming within my teams.
- · Elected position on the GTPNet Graduate Networking Society Committee - this organises events for all UBS Graduates.
- · Represented UBS at numerous Software Development and Technology Conferences.
- · Invited to represent UBS Group Technology at FinTech50 startup-event, liaising with media and startup founders.
- · Involved in encouraging Lean business ideas.
- · Volunteer mentor for UBS School and Undergraduate Interns.

#### July 2012 - August 2012 (10 Weeks)

## Position: Group Technology Summer Internship (Software Development) at UBS Investment Bank

- · Developed for the in-house Credit Derivatives · Completed solo project allocated 10 weeks, Settlements system.
- · Learnt and participated in Agile Development methods, including Scrum and Kanban.
- completed in 5 to add a new connection isolation mode to extend business-readiness tests for new Settlements system releases.

## July 2011 - July 2012

#### Position: 12 Month Industrial Placement - Developer at Nestlé UK, York

- Developed, supported and maintained the large bespoke systems utilised by Nestlé UK&I Logistics. Predominantly coding C#, VB, C, PL/SQL.
- · Analysed requests for new tools and systems.
- team's effectiveness.
- · Independently designed and developed an innovative new system to safely label loads, thereby obscuring sensitive identifying information. (see: "German Tank Problem")
- · Carried out independent projects to improve my · Introduced new systems using neoteric technologies - e.g. App notification to iPhone.

January 2010 - July 2010 Position: University of Birmingham Computer Science Student Ambassador September 2006 - April 2009 Position: Saturday Assistant and IT Specialist at an independent opticians

#### **Education and Qualifications**

• Graduated 2013 University of Birmingham (#1 for 'Computer Sciences and IT', Guardian University Guide 2014)

BSc(Hons) Computer Science with an Industrial Year - First Class Honours

AS: Maths, Critical Thinking Queen Elizabeth School for Boys, Barnet **A2:** Art, Computing, Physics

#### **Achievements and Awards**

- Evaluated as top in class for Technical Expertise at 3-week global Graduate Group Technology event at UBS Investment Bank and Wealth Management in Stamford, CT, and New York City.
  - Led my team in a 10-day Tech Exercise only team to complete a working model.
  - Evaluation commented on excellent leadership qualities, technical expertise and willingness to help [thus improving] others' contribution.
- · My Dissertation was very well received at University, and received the grade of First Class in its own right.
- Received £1000 Award for Academic Excellence from University of Birmingham.
- Participated in Young Rewired State at Google and featured in BBC News website article August 2009.
- Completed Duke of Edinburgh Gold Award in 2009. Presented by the Duke of Edinburgh on 30/11/10.
- Represented my University at the British University Karting Championships in 2010 2013 (A-team).
- Volunteered as a Youth Leader at local Mill Hill Youth Club after-school club 2007 2009.

## **Software Development Skills**

- · Very proficient in Java, its use with various Spring components and numerous Open Source libraries.
- Experience in other Object Orientated Design Knowledge of SOLID principles and good design patterns.
- Experience of Agile Development Methodologies in a business environment including Scrum & Kanban.
  - Use of User Stories and Specification By Example (SBEs) to ensure clients' needs are met.
  - Use of Pair Programming and striving for quality Clean Code.
- Test Driven Development
  - Knowledgable of Red, Green, Refactor; the 3As; Single Assert Rule; Good Test Composition; Test Readability and the role of Mocks.
  - Experience working with the JBehave Behaviour-Driven Development testing framework.
- · Good working knowledge of C# and .Net framework; Javascript (AngularJS, JQuery and server-side NodeJS); HTML and CSS.
- Experience in developing iOS Apps in Objective-C and Swift. (Part of my dissertation and for personal projects.)
- Familiar with Relational Databases (Oracle & Sybase), NoSQL (MongoDB, MarkLogic, Redis), Graph (Neo4J) and Elasticsearch.
- Familiar with Version Control Systems Git (with collaboration on GitHub) and Subversion (SVN).
- I am currently teaching myself Swift, Java 8 Streams, Erlang, Scala, Ruby, Python and Functional Programming techniques through personal projects.

## **Technology Conferences and Events**

At UBS, I was one of the lead organisers of their first Global Hackathon. The high-profile event ran in four regions with London winning the overall prize. My work received exposure across all divisions of the bank.

I have represented UBS at:

- Software Craftsmanship 2013 at Bletchley Park.
- · QCon London 2014 at The Queen Elizabeth II Conference Centre, Westminster.
- "Devs Love Bacon" at St Paul's, City of London.
- Devoxx London 2014 at Business Design Centre, Islington.
- FinTech50 October 2014 at UBS Conference Centre, Broadgate, City of London.

Israel Tech Challenge, 10-day programme during Summer 2014:

- I was selected as one of 30 top young technologists from hundreds of applications around the world.
- · The trip included visits and lectures from world-class universities, startups and international technology firms like Google, eBay, Checkpoint and many more.
- · At a 48-hour Hackathon held at PayPal's Tel Aviv office on the topic 'Smart Cities', my team's app to intelligently collect population data - was well received and showed a high level of technical complexity.

### **Leisure Activities**

Sport: At University, I was an active member of the Motor Sport Society. I represented my University in the A-team at the annual British University Karting Championships 2010 - 2013. I now head the Birmingham University Alumni Motor Sport Society. I also enjoy cycling, tennis, squash and skiing.

Hobbies: I have a keen interest in photography and have a popular Flickr profile ('adav') to showcase my photos. Periodically, I enrol in open-access Language courses - recently studying German for a year in 2012. I have played the guitar for many years and after taking up the ukelele, I now play weekly in a group jam in East London.